Two ghosts walk into the stadium tonight.
One has haunted Argentina's matches since nineteen seventy-eight.
The other has blessed Algeria's since independence.
Tonight... they finally meet.
In episode five, we predicted the kings would survive Morocco, one-nil.
Tonight — the champion of everything... against the nation football betrayed.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode six. Argentina versus Algeria.
Group J. The GOAT's last opening night.
And stay with me — because in the eighty-third minute of our story...
something happens that you will want to see twice.
First, the wound. Spain, nineteen eighty-two.
Algeria — a debutant — beats mighty West Germany two-one. The world gasps.
Three days later, West Germany and Austria walk onto the pitch...
already knowing the one score that saves them both.
Eighty minutes of passing in circles.
Algeria — eliminated without kicking a ball. They call it the Disgrace of Gijon.
And here is what nobody remembers: FIFA changed the rules because of it.
Every final group game since nineteen eighty-six kicks off at the same time...
because of what was done to Algeria.
Forty-four years later, the wounded nation finally meets football royalty...
on the same stage that betrayed them.
And what royalty. The world champions. The kings of everything.
Lionel Messi. Thirty-nine in this story.
The greatest who ever lived — wrapping the armband for his very last World Cup dance.
Julian Alvarez, the Spider, who hunts in packs.
Enzo and Mac Allister, the engine room of champions. And Dibu Martinez...
the wolf in the goalmouth.
They have touched heaven. Tonight they defend it.
But Algeria did not come to bow.
This is their golden generation — and they carry nineteen eighty-two in their blood.
Riyad Mahrez — the desert fox.
He conquered the Premier League with Leicester, ruled Europe with City...
then chose the desert over the throne.
Ismael Bennacer, the tiny metronome of Milan, ninety percent passing in his bones.
And Amine Gouiri — silk and hunger in one body.
Forty-four years of waiting walks onto the pitch tonight.
And the duel of duels: Messi against Mahrez. The GOAT against the Fox.
Two left feet... that both bend the laws of physics.
Our prediction — built on Gijon, on champions' steel, and on one wolf in the goalmouth.
Watch closely.
Fifty-second minute. Enzo finds the Spider — Alvarez spins — finishes. One-nil.
The champions breathe.
But Algeria does not break. They wait. They remember. And the clock crawls toward...
the eighty-third minute.
Here it is. The moment we promised. Mahrez. Right flank.
He cuts inside — the move every defender knows is coming... and nobody can stop.
The curl rises... dips... the whole stadium stops breathing —
DIBU! Fingertips! Off the post!
The wolf of the goalmouth swallows the desert's last spell!
Full time in our story: one-nil Argentina.
But Mahrez walks off to applause from BOTH ends. Some wounds heal... with respect.
Do you agree? Comment GOAT if Argentina go back-to-back.
Comment FOX if Algeria shocks Group J.
And the two ghosts?
Legends six and seven — El Abuelo de la Bombonera, seen at every Argentina match since seventy-eight...
and Le Vieux Fennec, whose raised cane has blessed Algeria since independence.
Tonight they watched together. Collect them BOTH inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple. Your picks change everything.
Hit like — send this to the friend who says Messi is finished.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.