On a tiny island you could drive across in an hour, an old man once taught children to play football on the sand.
Tonight, those children are at the World Cup.
And he is watching.
Last time, we predicted Australia and Turkey would trade blows and draw.
Tonight — the oldest story in football. David... and the machine.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode twelve. Germany versus Curacao.
The giant... against the island.
And stay with me — because in the thirty-fourth minute, a man from a tiny island makes the save of the tournament.
First, the giant. Germany. Four World Cup titles.
A conveyor belt of talent that simply never stops producing.
And now their most thrilling generation in decades — led by a boy they call Bambi.
Jamal Musiala, the Dribble King, whose slalom runs draw gasps from opponents and comparisons to Messi from everyone else.
Beside him, Florian Wirtz — a hundred million euros of vision, seeing passes from another dimension.
Germany have not lost a World Cup opener this century.
But across the pitch stands a nation of a hundred and fifty thousand people.
Curacao.
An island you could drive across in an hour — at their first World Cup in history.
But do not pity them.
Their players carry Dutch passports and Dutch football DNA — graduates of the same Ajax and Feyenoord academies that taught the world Total Football.
Small islands, they like to say, produce big hearts.
And in goal stands a man who has spent a career proving exactly that.
Eloy Room. The Columbus Crew legend.
Six-foot-two of calm, carrying an entire island on his gloves.
Juninho Bacuna drives the midfield for every child who ever kicked a ball on a Caribbean beach.
Rangelo Janga reads danger like a book.
They are fearless, technical, and they cannot quite believe they are here.
That makes them dangerous.
When the minnow stares into the eyes of the whale... and refuses to blink.
And the duel inside the match: Musiala against Room. The Dribble King...
against the island's wall. Magic against defiance.
Our prediction — built on four stars, on Total Football roots, and on one impossible save.
Watch.
Thirty-fourth minute.
Musiala glides past two — the ball breaks to Wirtz — he curls it for the top corner, surely a goal —
ROOM! He flies — and tips it over the bar!
Three thousand Curacao fans erupt as if they have won the World Cup!
But the machine does not stop. Wave after wave. Musiala finishes.
Wirtz adds a second. Havertz makes it three.
Germany are simply too much. The class of a giant, in full flow.
Three-nil at full time, in our story.
But the night does not belong to the scoreline.
It belongs to Eloy Room — who reminded a giant that the fight was real.
Some teams lose the match... and still win the day.
Do you agree? Comment MACHINE if Germany go all the way this summer.
Comment DAVID if Curacao's pride steals your heart.
And the old man on the sand? Legend number twelve: the Beach Keeper.
He taught the island to dream with a ball at its feet.
Tonight, his children stood toe to toe with a giant. Collect him inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple — like Curacao tonight.
Hit like — send this to the friend who always roots for the little guy.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.