Her torch has never gone out. Since nineteen ninety...
at every American World Cup match... she has been standing there. Watching.
Waiting for this exact night.
Tonight, Liberty comes home.
In episode three, we PREDICTED respect in Toronto — no goals, one swap of shirts.
Tonight... it is America's turn.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode four.
The United States versus Paraguay. Group D. AT&T Stadium, Texas.
Eighty thousand voices under one colossal roof. And hiding inside this fixture...
is the oldest secret in World Cup history.
Listen carefully. The year is nineteen thirty. The very FIRST World Cup.
And in Montevideo... the United States face Paraguay.
America wins three nil.
And a twenty-year-old named Bert Patenaude scores all three...
the first hat-trick in World Cup history.
But here is the twist: for seventy-six years, the record books gave that honor to an Argentine.
Only in two thousand six did FIFA finally correct it. The first hat-trick ever...
belongs to an American. Against Paraguay.
Ninety-six years later... the rematch. Same two nations. Biggest stage on Earth.
Meet the hosts. The golden generation that promised America a football future...
and now has to deliver it.
Christian Pulisic. The captain.
He carried American soccer from its darkest hours to this very night — and Milan made him sharper than ever.
Folarin Balogun, the cold-blooded number nine.
Weston McKennie, the engine that never stops. Tyler Adams, the heartbeat.
A home World Cup. Eighty thousand believers.
No more promises — tonight they deliver.
But Paraguay is the quietest team in Group D. No hype. No headlines.
Just cold-eyed steel from South American qualifying.
Miguel Almiron — six years in the Premier League.
He knows these American stadiums... intimately.
Julio Enciso, the young wizard from Brighton, dances with the recklessness of youth.
And Gustavo Gomez... is simply a wall.
They know Pulisic. They know the machine. And they are not afraid.
So here is the duel: the Captain against the Wonderkid. Pulisic's burden...
against Enciso's freedom. The weight of hosting against nothing to lose.
And our prediction — built on that history, on home pressure, and on Paraguay's iron defense.
Watch.
Thirty-fourth minute. Pulisic feints, explodes, and slides it across — BALOGUN!
One nil! AT&T Stadium detonates!
But remember the steel.
Sixty-first minute — Almiron, the man who knows America best, silences eighty thousand.
One — one.
And then... the seventy-eighth minute arrives.
The Texas heat presses down like a hand.
Pulisic surges — Gomez blocks — and the ball falls... to Enciso. Forty yards out.
He looks up. The American defense is scrambling.
And right here... the story stops. Because what happens next decides everything.
So tell us YOUR ending. Comment ONE if it stays one-one.
Comment TWO if the kid from Brighton breaks eighty thousand hearts.
Our call: the hosts survive. One-one. Walls like Gomez bend...
but Texas nights do not break.
And now — remember her? Legend number four: The Liberty Fan.
Every American World Cup match since nineteen ninety. The flame never went out.
Tonight, it burned brighter than ever. Collect her inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple. Your picks change everything.
Hit like — send this to the friend who doubts American soccer.
And subscribe: next... BRAZIL. And we saw magic.