He has carried a single black star since nineteen fifty-seven.
The year a small nation looked the British Empire in the eye... and walked free.
Tonight, the empire talks back.
In episode seven, we predicted Brazil would beat Haiti four-one — but Haiti scored the goal of the night.
Tonight... the colony meets the crown.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode eight. England versus Ghana.
Group L. Football's inventors against football's defiance.
And stay with me — because in the sixty-seventh minute of our story, one man throws his whole body across history.
First, the truth. Nineteen fifty-seven.
Ghana becomes the FIRST nation south of the Sahara to win independence from Britain.
Fast forward. Twenty eleven. Wembley. England host Ghana for the very first time.
Eighty thousand seats... and half of them turn red, gold and green.
England lead. Then, the ninety-first minute — Asamoah Gyan.
The away team silences the home of football. One-one. Wembley belongs to Ghana.
And do not forget twenty-ten.
Ghana, seconds from becoming the first African team in a World Cup semifinal — denied by a hand on the line.
Tonight, for the very first time, they meet at a World Cup.
The conversation finally happens on the biggest stage of all.
So meet the inventors — the men who gave the world this game.
Harry Kane.
England's greatest-ever scorer — still hunting the medal that completes him.
Jude Bellingham, the golden boy of Madrid, who plays like he was born for the biggest nights.
Phil Foden bends reality. And Bukayo Saka — who turned cruelty into greatness.
Talent for a tournament. And a weight only England carries.
But Ghana did not come to play a supporting role.
The Black Stars carry a whole continent's pride into the light.
Thomas Partey — the general.
Years in the Premier League proving, over and over, that African footballers belong at the very top.
Inaki Williams, who chose Ghana over Spain.
Antoine Semenyo, forged in the league England invented.
And young Issahaku — they whisper the name of Abedi Pele.
This is not an underdog. This is a reckoning.
And the duel inside the match: Bellingham against Partey. The heir to the throne...
against the man who guards the gate. Heart against heart.
Our prediction — built on nineteen fifty-seven, on Wembley, and on one man on the line.
Watch closely.
Thirty-fourth minute. Foden threads it, Kane turns — finishes. One-nil England.
The crown settles on its head.
But Ghana does not bow. They press. They believe. And the clock crawls toward...
the sixty-seventh minute.
Here it is. The moment we promised.
Saka flies down the right, cuts it back — Kane rises — header, goalbound, surely two-nil —
The whole stadium holds its breath —
PARTEY! Off the line!
The general throws his whole body across history and clears it! Ghana SURVIVES!
And then — the eighty-eighth minute. Just like twenty eleven. Ghana strike late.
One-one. The Black Stars make the empire listen all over again.
Do you agree? Comment LIONS if England top Group L.
Comment STARS if Ghana's draw shocks the world.
And the elder with the single black star?
Legend number nine: the Keeper of fifty-seven.
He has stood for every Ghana side since freedom itself.
Tonight, he watched the empire answered. Collect him inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple — like Ghana tonight.
Hit like — send this to the friend who thinks they know who invented football.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.