In the desert, they say a falcon always returns...
to the hand that never stopped believing.
For one old man, that hand has waited a very long time.
Tonight, the falcon flies.
Last time, we predicted Brazil would beat Haiti — and a supermarket worker stole the night.
Tonight, a wounded host... against a silent machine.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode nine. Qatar versus Switzerland.
The desert fox against the alpine eagle.
And stay with me — because in the seventy-eighth minute of our story, one free kick freezes an entire nation.
First, the wound. Twenty twenty-two. Qatar hosts the World Cup...
and loses every single match. The worst host performance in history.
Four years carrying that shame.
But the world forgot something: Qatar are the back-to-back kings of Asia — champions in twenty nineteen, and again in twenty twenty-three.
Their conductor, Akram Afif, was the best player on the continent.
This is no minnow. This is a wounded champion.
And Switzerland? The quietest machine in football.
At the last Euros, they knocked out world champions France...
and broke a nation on penalties.
Tonight, one of them needs only a point to survive.
The other has nothing left to lose.
And nothing to lose is the most dangerous thing in all of sport.
Meet the desert fox. Qatar — technical, patient, fearless.
Akram Afif, the magician who finds space that should not exist.
Almoez Ali, the record-breaking striker.
And Hassan Al-Haydos, the veteran captain... playing his very last World Cup match.
Patience. Precision. And absolutely no fear.
But the alpine eagle does not panic.
Switzerland reach the knockout rounds again and again — built like a Swiss watch.
Granit Xhaka, the general who runs the tempo. Manuel Akanji, elegance in defense.
And Dan Ndoye — electric feet on the right wing.
Breel Embolo waits for one chance. Young Ardon Jashari drives the engine.
They do not dazzle. They just... win.
One mistake tonight ends a World Cup.
And the duel inside the match: Afif against Xhaka. The artist against the architect.
Imagination... against order.
Our prediction — built on the wound of twenty twenty-two, and on Swiss steel.
Watch closely.
Thirty-fourth minute.
Afif splits the defense — Almoez Ali, one-on-one — but drags it wide!
The golden chance... gone.
Fifty-second minute. Switzerland strike like a watch.
Ndoye beats his man, cuts it back —
Embolo! A thumping header! One-nil Switzerland. Swiss precision, Swiss result.
But here it comes... the seventy-eighth minute.
Afif stands over the free kick. Twenty-two yards.
The whole desert holds its breath —
He curls it over the wall — SOMMER! Fingertips! Onto the bar!
The human wall denies the magician!
Full time: one-nil Switzerland. The eagle advances.
But Qatar walks off to an ovation — twenty twenty-two was a beginning, not an ending.
Do you agree? Comment EAGLE if Switzerland go far this summer.
Comment FALCON if Qatar shocks the group.
And the old man with the falcon? Legend number nine: the Falconer of the Desert.
He believed in Qatar... long before they had a stadium at all.
Tonight, his falcon flew. Collect him inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple — like Qatar tonight.
Hit like — send this to the friend who wrote Qatar off.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.