Listen. Do you hear the drum?
It has been beating the same rhythm since nineteen seventy-four...
at every Haiti match. Without missing one.
Tonight... it beats for Brazil.
In episode six, we predicted the champions would survive Algeria, one-nil.
Tonight — the kings of football... meet the nation that refuses to break.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode seven. Brazil versus Haiti.
Group C. Five stars against one unbreakable heart.
And stay with me — because in first-half stoppage time of our story...
a supermarket worker does something impossible.
First, the history. Nineteen seventy-four.
Haiti — the first Caribbean nation ever at a World Cup — walks out against mighty Italy.
Italy's goalkeeper is Dino Zoff.
He has not conceded a goal in one thousand one hundred and forty-two minutes.
The longest wall in football history.
Forty-sixth minute. Emmanuel Sanon runs onto a pass... rounds Zoff... and scores.
The wall falls.
Haiti lost that match.
But Sanon's goal became a flag — proof, forever, that the small can wound the giant.
Fifty-two years later — through earthquakes, through everything — Haiti is BACK.
And waiting for them... the kings.
Five World Cups. The only nation that has played in every single one.
Vinicius Junior — the dancer. Twenty-five. Champions League royalty.
His feet move faster than the music.
Neymar — thirty-four, his very last World Cup, playing with the freedom of a man with nothing left to prove.
Raphinha tortures the flanks. And Alisson... the calmest man alive.
For Brazil, anything less than victory... is a national emergency.
But Haiti did not cross the sea to bow.
This is the first Caribbean fairy tale in fifty-two years — and it has teeth.
Duckens Nazon. A scout found him stacking shelves in a supermarket.
Now he leads a World Cup attack — wearing that story like armor.
Derrick Etienne Junior — born in America, he chose Haiti.
Johny Placide, the wall of Port-au-Prince.
And all of them know Sanon's story by heart.
A nation that survives everything... fears nothing.
And the duel inside the match: Neymar against Nazon. The man who has everything...
against the man who came from nothing. Both play for pure joy.
Our prediction — built on five stars, on samba... and on one drum that never stops.
Watch.
Twenty-three minutes — Vinicius, goal. Thirty-four — a Neymar free kick.
Forty-one — Raphinha. Three-nil.
Three-nil before half time. The match is over. Everyone knows it...
everyone except one man.
Stoppage time. Nazon takes the ball on the halfway line.
Not fast, by Brazilian standards. Not skillful, by Brazilian standards. But Haitian.
Past one. Past two. He shoots from the edge of the box —
TOP CORNER! NAZON!
The supermarket worker scores against BRAZIL — and the whole stadium rises!
Brazil add a fourth — Neymar, barely a celebration.
Because tonight the scoreline is not the story.
The story is the goal that made the world stand up.
Do you agree? Comment SAMBA if Brazil win the Hexa this summer.
Comment SPIRIT if Nazon's goal is the moment of the tournament.
And the drum? Legend number eight: Le Tambouye de soixante-quatorze.
They say he beat that drum in the stands in nineteen seventy-four...
and he has never stopped.
Tonight, the drum beat for a miracle. Collect him inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple — like Haiti tonight.
Hit like — send this to the friend who stopped believing in miracles.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.