Somewhere high in the stands, an old piper has played at every Scotland World Cup since nineteen seventy-four.
He has never once played a song of celebration.
Tonight, he is praying that changes.
Last time, we predicted Switzerland would edge Qatar one-nil.
Tonight — two of football's bravest underdogs, fighting just to survive.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode ten. Haiti versus Scotland.
The battle of the nearly-men.
And stay with me — because the final whistle of this one... makes BOTH teams dance.
First, the curse.
Scotland has qualified for the World Cup more times than any nation on Earth...
without EVER reaching the knockout stage.
Nineteen seventy-four: unbeaten, and still eliminated.
Nineteen seventy-eight: one of the greatest goals ever scored...
and they went home anyway.
Fifty years of the bravest heartbreak in football.
And the old piper has played through every single tear.
Haiti's pain is quieter, but just as deep. One World Cup in nineteen seventy-four.
Then a fifty-two-year silence.
Tonight, both nations need a win to survive. Two underdogs.
One ticket out of the group. Everything on the line.
And nobody fights like a team with nothing but pride to lose.
Meet the Tartan heart.
Scotland — fury, running, and fifty years of unfinished business.
Scott McTominay, the Serie A Player of the Year, who left a Manchester bench to conquer Italy.
John McGinn, all craft and chaos.
And Andy Robertson, the captain who never, ever stops running.
Heart. Fury. And a nation that refuses to quit.
But Haiti did not cross an ocean to bow.
The Caribbean's unbreakable team plays for eleven million dreaming hearts.
Duckens Nazon, the striker who stacked supermarket shelves before football saved him — playing like this is his only World Cup.
Derrick Etienne Junior pulls the strings — he chose Haiti when America was calling.
This team is pure, fearless defiance.
Two nations who know this might be their only night.
And the duel inside the match: McTominay against Nazon. Italy's best...
against the man from the supermarket. Pure heart against pure hunger.
Our prediction — built on fifty years of Scottish pain and Haitian defiance.
Watch closely.
Seventeenth minute. Robertson's cross — McTominay, near post — header — GOAL!
Scotland leads! The Tartan Army erupts!
But Haiti does not fold. Nazon fights for everything.
And the clock ticks past the hour...
Sixty-third minute. A long ball.
Nazon holds off his man, turns, shoots — a deflection — it loops up...
and over the keeper!
ONE—ONE! The supermarket striker again!
An entire Caribbean nation explodes into dance!
Eighty-ninth minute — Shankland turns and shoots — OFF THE POST!
Inches from breaking Scottish hearts again.
Full time in our story: one-one. And the cruelest twist — BOTH teams are eliminated.
And yet... nobody leaves.
Do you agree? Comment TARTAN if Scotland finally break the curse one day.
Comment HAITI if the Caribbean dream lives on.
And the old piper? Legend number ten: the Lone Piper.
Fifty years of heartbreak, and tonight... he finally plays a song of joy.
Because some battles are won just by showing up to fight.
Collect him inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple.
Hit like — send this to the friend whose team never gives up.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.