Deep in the Amazon, there is a man crowned with feathers.
They say he saw all five of Brazil's world titles... before they happened.
Tonight, he has a sixth vision.
In episode four, we predicted a one-one storm in Texas.
Tonight, the tournament stops pretending... because BRAZIL is here.
Welcome back to WorldCup twenty-six Legends, episode five. Brazil versus Morocco.
Group C. And the whole planet is watching.
One hundred ninety-six million Brazilians. Thirty-seven million Moroccans. One ball.
And a secret the kings of football would rather forget.
Five stars. Fifty-eight. Sixty-two. Seventy. Ninety-four. Two thousand two.
No nation has more.
But look closer at that last star... two thousand two.
Brazil has not touched the trophy in twenty-four years.
The longest wait in their history.
And Morocco?
In twenty twenty-two they became the FIRST African and Arab nation ever to reach a World Cup semifinal.
Spain — gone. Portugal — gone.
Now the secret. March, twenty twenty-three. Tangier. The last time these two met...
Morocco WON. Two-one. The first Moroccan victory over Brazil in history.
And the man who created the first goal that night... is on the pitch again tonight.
So meet the kings. The yellow machine chasing the Hexa — the sixth star.
Vinicius Junior. Twenty-five. Two Champions League titles.
His dribbling defies physics — his joy is a love letter to the beautiful game.
Neymar — thirty-four now, dropping deep, seeing passes nobody else can imagine.
Raphinha stretches the world. And behind them all...
Alisson, the calmest man in football.
When Brazil plays, the world stops. That is the law.
But Morocco does not stop for anyone. Compact. Disciplined.
Fearless — and they have already beaten these kings once.
Achraf Hakimi — arguably the best right-back on Earth.
Born in Madrid, heart in Rabat. His penalty eliminated Spain itself.
Hakim Ziyech, the wand of a left foot.
Sofyan Amrabat, the engine of the semifinal run.
And El Khannouss — the kid who unlocked Brazil in Tangier.
This is not an underdog. This is a trap.
And the duel inside the match: Vinicius against Hakimi.
The fastest winger alive against the fastest defender alive. Lightning...
against lightning.
The Prophet's vision — built on five stars, one drought, and one night in Tangier.
Watch.
Sixty-seventh minute. Morocco counter. Hakimi — SHOT! Alisson saves!
The rebound — En-Nesyri header — CLEARED OFF THE LINE! Inches from silence.
The kings are shaking. The Lions can smell it. And the clock keeps breathing...
Seventy-eighth minute. Neymar. Thirty-five yards. Three defenders around him...
and he sees what nobody sees.
A no-look pass that bends the laws of physics — VINI — cuts inside — GOAL! One-nil!
A billion voices exhale at once!
Full time. The Prophet's vision: Brazil survive, one-nil.
But hear this — Morocco walked toe-to-toe with the kings...
and the Lions' roar echoes louder than the scoreline.
Do you agree with the vision? Comment HEXA if Brazil wins it all this summer.
Comment LIONS if Morocco tops Group C instead.
And the man with the feathers? Legend number five: The Feathered Prophet.
Five visions. Five stars. They say Pele's spirit speaks through him.
Tonight he saw the sixth begin. Collect him inside the game.
Which brings us to YOU.
At WorldCup twenty-six dot world, pick three of the forty-eight nations — and every goal they score...
scores for you.
Free to play. Live leaderboard. Underdogs pay triple. Your picks change everything.
Hit like — send this to the friend who thinks Brazil is unbeatable.
And subscribe: the legends are only beginning.